[
  {
    "question": "Define <strong>ceiling price</strong>.",
    "answer": "The ceiling price is the maximum price that a purchaser is willing to pay for a property."
  },
  {
    "question": "The _________ method of appraisal bases the value of the subject property on the _________ of similar properties which have _____ recently.",
    "answer": "The <strong>comparative</strong> method of appraisal bases the value of the subject property on the <strong>price</strong> of similar properties which have <strong>sold</strong> recently."
  },
  {
    "question": "Appraisers are typically called upon to estimate objective values, which are categorized into the following:",
    "answer": "insurable value, lending value, taxable value, actual value, and market value."
  },
  {
    "question": "An appraiser must understand the purpose of the appraisal assignment. A ____________ reason, for example, for expropriation or taxation purposes or a ____________ reason, such as buying, selling, leasing, or developing a property. ",
    "answer": "An appraiser must understand the purpose of the appraisal assignment. A <strong>statutory</strong> reason, for example, for expropriation or taxation purposes or a <strong>market</strong> reason, such as buying, selling, leasing, or developing a property."
  },
  {
    "question": "Highest and best use is defined as the use of land which, within all ____________ (for example, zoning bylaws), will provide the maximum ______ _______ during the foreseeable future.",
    "answer": "Highest and best use is defined as the use of land which, within all <strong>constraints</strong> (for example, zoning bylaws), will provide the maximum <strong>net return</strong> during the foreseeable future."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is <strong>latent value</strong>? ",
    "answer": "Latent value is the value possessed by a property which has potential for redevelopment because it is currently not employed as its highest and best use."
  },
  {
    "question": "The direct comparison approach is based on the principle of __________. ",
    "answer": "The direct comparison approach is based on the principle of <strong>substitution</strong>."
  },
  {
    "question": "An estimate of the value of an interest in real property is called:",
    "answer": "an <strong>appraisal</strong> (or <strong>property valuation</strong>)."
  },
  {
    "question": "Define <strong>cost approach</strong>. ",
    "answer": "A method of appraisal which determines the value of a property by adding the market value of the site to the cost of replacing the existing building."
  },
  {
    "question": "When value is expressed a lump sum, it is referred to as a ____________ ____________ appraisal.",
    "answer": "When value is expressed as a lump sum, it is referred to as a <strong>capital value</strong> appraisal."
  }
]